<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2022-12-04T18:30:27-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Unseen</title><subtitle>Stories of how we are losing ourselves.</subtitle><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><entry><title type="html">Optogenetics and Reward Processes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/optogentics-and-reward-processes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Optogenetics and Reward Processes" /><published>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/optogentics-and-reward-processes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/optogentics-and-reward-processes/">&lt;p&gt;we optogenetically drove well-defined dopamine neurons in the mouse in different temporal patterns during free behavior, and found parameters that were sufficient to drive reinforced behavior (for example, in the absence of any other cue or reward, healthy animals simply chose to spend more time in places where they had received particular kinds of optogenetic bursting activity in dopamine neurons). This work is relevant to hedonic (pleasure-related) pathologies involved in depression (as in my depressed patient who could no longer even enjoy seeing her grandchildren, otherwise one of the most rewarding experiences known to humankind) and in substance abuse, as well as in healthy reward processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/optogenetics-controlling/&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">we optogenetically drove well-defined dopamine neurons in the mouse in different temporal patterns during free behavior, and found parameters that were sufficient to drive reinforced behavior (for example, in the absence of any other cue or reward, healthy animals simply chose to spend more time in places where they had received particular kinds of optogenetic bursting activity in dopamine neurons). This work is relevant to hedonic (pleasure-related) pathologies involved in depression (as in my depressed patient who could no longer even enjoy seeing her grandchildren, otherwise one of the most rewarding experiences known to humankind) and in substance abuse, as well as in healthy reward processes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Perception</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/perception/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Perception" /><published>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/perception</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/perception/">&lt;p&gt;Perception is created in part through the simultaneous action of thousands of feature detector neurons — specialized neurons, located in the visual cortex, that respond to the strength, angles, shapes, edges, and movements of a visual stimulus (Kelsey, 1997; Livingstone &amp;amp; Hubel, 1988). The feature detectors work in parallel, each performing a specialized function. When faced with a red square, for instance, the parallel line feature detectors, the horizontal line feature detectors, and the red colour feature detectors all become activated. This activation is then passed on to other parts of the visual cortex, where other neurons compare the information supplied by the feature detectors with images stored in memory. Suddenly, in a flash of recognition, the many neurons fire together, creating the single image of the red square that we experience (Rodriguez et al., 1999).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">Perception is created in part through the simultaneous action of thousands of feature detector neurons — specialized neurons, located in the visual cortex, that respond to the strength, angles, shapes, edges, and movements of a visual stimulus (Kelsey, 1997; Livingstone &amp;amp; Hubel, 1988). The feature detectors work in parallel, each performing a specialized function. When faced with a red square, for instance, the parallel line feature detectors, the horizontal line feature detectors, and the red colour feature detectors all become activated. This activation is then passed on to other parts of the visual cortex, where other neurons compare the information supplied by the feature detectors with images stored in memory. Suddenly, in a flash of recognition, the many neurons fire together, creating the single image of the red square that we experience (Rodriguez et al., 1999).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quiet Quitting</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/quiet-quitting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quiet Quitting" /><published>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/quiet-quitting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/quiet-quitting/">&lt;p&gt;Sean really didn’t want to be bothered with having a job, but his dad wouldn’t pay his rent anymore. So, now he was forced to find only the amount of employment he needed to cover his rent, utilities, and food–he didn’t have many other needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had been employed at RiseTech, a big data company for a little over a year now. It was a completely remote gig for a company in another town. For the first six months he’d work about half time to make it look like he was a good employee, but after that he just pretty played the his games and chatted with his friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, after 14 months, he was quiet quitting. This is what he told his friends and talked about on Reddit. he was taking a stance against the man. Really, he just didn’t feel like working or be bothered with quitting and looking for a new job–until he had to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">Sean really didn’t want to be bothered with having a job, but his dad wouldn’t pay his rent anymore. So, now he was forced to find only the amount of employment he needed to cover his rent, utilities, and food–he didn’t have many other needs.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retinal Rods</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/retinal-rods/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retinal Rods" /><published>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/retinal-rods</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/retinal-rods/">&lt;p&gt;Rods are visual neurons that specialize in detecting black, white, and gray colours. There are about 120 million rods in each eye. The rods do not provide a lot of detail about the images we see, but because they are highly sensitive to shorter-waved (darker) and weak light, they help us see in dim light — for instance, at night. Because the rods are located primarily around the edges of the retina, they are particularly active in peripheral vision (when you need to see something at night, try looking away from what you want to see). Cones are visual neurons that are specialized in detecting fine detail and colours. The five million or so cones in each eye enable us to see in colour, but they operate best in bright light. The cones are located primarily in and around the fovea, which is the central point of the retina.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">Rods are visual neurons that specialize in detecting black, white, and gray colours. There are about 120 million rods in each eye. The rods do not provide a lot of detail about the images we see, but because they are highly sensitive to shorter-waved (darker) and weak light, they help us see in dim light — for instance, at night. Because the rods are located primarily around the edges of the retina, they are particularly active in peripheral vision (when you need to see something at night, try looking away from what you want to see). Cones are visual neurons that are specialized in detecting fine detail and colours. The five million or so cones in each eye enable us to see in colour, but they operate best in bright light. The cones are located primarily in and around the fovea, which is the central point of the retina.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fear of being alone</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fear-of-being-alone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fear of being alone" /><published>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fear-of-being-alone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fear-of-being-alone/">&lt;p&gt;The fear of being alone is a fear that affects many people. This is a belief that causes us to conform to what others think, just so that they will accept us. For example, if we are jokers or pranksters, but our friends are embarrassed about us, then we’ll try to change and repress that part of us, just so we don’t feel alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, we choose to be invisible so that others will accept us. However, we should ask ourselves: do we really want to be with people who don’t accept us as we really are? And yet being alone is like leaving our comfort zone. That is why we are so afraid of not finding more friends, a partner or a person who really accepts us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if we decide to change and blot out our real selves, then there’ll come a time when we’ll ask ourselves who we really are. Choosing to be like other people expect us to be is almost like a betrayal of ourselves. It is a type of rejection of our true self that will cause us great upset and unease in the long run. In order to rediscover ourselves, we’ll have to go through a process that will mean us having to face what we really fear. It will be a complex, but eventually satisfying, path when we finally reach that goal. There is nothing more beautiful than truly finding ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">The fear of being alone is a fear that affects many people. This is a belief that causes us to conform to what others think, just so that they will accept us. For example, if we are jokers or pranksters, but our friends are embarrassed about us, then we’ll try to change and repress that part of us, just so we don’t feel alone.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Control of Cellular Biochemistry</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/control-of-cellular-biochestry/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Control of Cellular Biochemistry" /><published>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/control-of-cellular-biochestry</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/control-of-cellular-biochestry/">&lt;p&gt;Optogenetics in common usage refers specifically to the control of neuronal firing with opsins, and as control of neuronal firing with opsins postdates and utilizes distinct mechanisms from control of cellular biochemistry with photoproteins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Optogenetics is the combination of genetics and optics to control well-defined events within specific cells of living tissue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optogenetics&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">Optogenetics in common usage refers specifically to the control of neuronal firing with opsins, and as control of neuronal firing with opsins postdates and utilizes distinct mechanisms from control of cellular biochemistry with photoproteins</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Difference Between Rods and Cones</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/difference-between-rods-and-cones/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Difference Between Rods and Cones" /><published>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/difference-between-rods-and-cones</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/difference-between-rods-and-cones/">&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate the difference between rods and cones in attention to detail, choose a word in this text and focus on it. Do you notice that the words a few inches to the side seem more blurred? This is because the word you are focusing on strikes the detail-oriented cones, while the words surrounding it strike the less-detail-oriented rods, which are located on the periphery.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">To demonstrate the difference between rods and cones in attention to detail, choose a word in this text and focus on it. Do you notice that the words a few inches to the side seem more blurred? This is because the word you are focusing on strikes the detail-oriented cones, while the words surrounding it strike the less-detail-oriented rods, which are located on the periphery.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fear of awakening the envy of others</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fear-of-awakening-the-envy-of-others/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fear of awakening the envy of others" /><published>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fear-of-awakening-the-envy-of-others</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fear-of-awakening-the-envy-of-others/">&lt;p&gt;We are all unique in some way, with some special ability or natural gift that enables us to do things we would like to be recognized for. However, we know that if we stand out then that can cause envy in other people. If this happens then we will no doubt have to face criticism, judgments and rejections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some people, depending on their past experiences, this can be unbearable, as we tend to look to others for their approval. The desire to shine, but also the fear of doing so, causes us to find ourselves caught between two options. Either to shine and make ourselves and our abilities known, or to become invisible and follow other people’s expectations.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">We are all unique in some way, with some special ability or natural gift that enables us to do things we would like to be recognized for. However, we know that if we stand out then that can cause envy in other people. If this happens then we will no doubt have to face criticism, judgments and rejections.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Switching Research</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/switching-research/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Switching Research" /><published>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/switching-research</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/switching-research/">&lt;p&gt;It seems disturbing to say, but Jerome was happy to move onto research involving online sex workers. It was an important area of research that will benefit humanity, but it was something he could do from mostly at home and online. But, most importantly he wouldn’t have to go into those prison walls anymore to speak with prisoners who were languishing in solitary confinment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jerome had been doing research on the physical impacts of solitary confiment on prisoners, working to understand what it was doing to these human beings we’ve decided aren’t worthy of being part of our world. His work had impacted legislation across 15 separate states, and had made a singificant impact on the world, but working in prisons each day was beginning to take a physical and mental toll on Jerome as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His new project was also funded by his department at the university where he worked, and sparked his interest because it was about the impacts of our online world. Jerome was a late bloomer when it came to the World Wide Web, but he has long been concerned about the impact the web was having on society. He was concerned enough to go online and better understand how the web worked, so he could take his brand of research online and help make sense of things–little did he know just how big this online world was, and how significant an impact it would have on all of us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">It seems disturbing to say, but Jerome was happy to move onto research involving online sex workers. It was an important area of research that will benefit humanity, but it was something he could do from mostly at home and online. But, most importantly he wouldn’t have to go into those prison walls anymore to speak with prisoners who were languishing in solitary confinment.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fear of losing our public identity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fear-of-losing-our-public-identity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fear of losing our public identity" /><published>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fear-of-losing-our-public-identity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fear-of-losing-our-public-identity/">&lt;p&gt;If in our childhood our family has taught us that we don’t deserve anything that we receive, then it is very likely that we will grow up thinking and acting accordingly. In this way we may not only think that we don’t deserve a gift, but that we aren’t worthy of affection either. We will have adopted an identity of “no merit”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strangely, we are terrified of losing what we were told we were. We are scared of losing what we don’t really identify with, that identity that we have been almost obliged to accept. That’s why it’s so hard for us to make any sort of progress sometimes. We have built ourselves a world which functions according to who we think we are, and who we have been told we are. Because of this, and without realizing it, nor wanting to do so, we flee from any signs of affection.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">If in our childhood our family has taught us that we don’t deserve anything that we receive, then it is very likely that we will grow up thinking and acting accordingly. In this way we may not only think that we don’t deserve a gift, but that we aren’t worthy of affection either. We will have adopted an identity of “no merit”.</summary></entry></feed>