<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2022-12-11T14:05:13-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Unseen</title><subtitle>Stories of how we are losing ourselves.</subtitle><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><entry><title type="html">Escaping Notice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/escaping-notice/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Escaping Notice" /><published>2022-12-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/escaping-notice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/escaping-notice/">&lt;p&gt;Escaping notice need not be about complacent isolation, mindless conformity or humiliating anonymity. When circumstance confers invisibility upon us, perhaps it is something to appreciate and even welcome, as some iteration of the small imprint, low-impact living it makes sense to aspire to. Or possibly as a more profound poise, a fuller appreciation for our place in the greater scheme of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think of the walking stick again. When it moves, its shadow is the shadow of a branch, its incremental motion suggesting nothing more than the breeze hitting a bit of bough. It may just be one ordinary thing disguised as another, but it has a lightness of being, a composure, and all the grace of going unseen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">Escaping notice need not be about complacent isolation, mindless conformity or humiliating anonymity. When circumstance confers invisibility upon us, perhaps it is something to appreciate and even welcome, as some iteration of the small imprint, low-impact living it makes sense to aspire to. Or possibly as a more profound poise, a fuller appreciation for our place in the greater scheme of things.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Camoflouge and the Natural World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/camoflouge-and-the-natural-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Camoflouge and the Natural World" /><published>2022-12-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/camoflouge-and-the-natural-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/camoflouge-and-the-natural-world/">&lt;p&gt;Throughout the natural world, the capacity for camouflage and the ability to recede into the background come with lavish beauty and biological aplomb. Consider the arctic foxes and hares that turn white before snowfall. Or the baroque patterning of Indonesian crabs that mimic the coral in which they live. Or the octopus with cells beneath its skin that can change color to simulate that of the surrounding marine life. You could call these all extravaganzas of obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">Throughout the natural world, the capacity for camouflage and the ability to recede into the background come with lavish beauty and biological aplomb. Consider the arctic foxes and hares that turn white before snowfall. Or the baroque patterning of Indonesian crabs that mimic the coral in which they live. Or the octopus with cells beneath its skin that can change color to simulate that of the surrounding marine life. You could call these all extravaganzas of obscurity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Attention</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/attention/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Attention" /><published>2022-12-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/attention</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/attention/">&lt;p&gt;We live in a time and culture that value display and are largely indifferent to the virtues of passing unnoticed. If we don’t get the interest, attention and recognition we think we deserve — whether we are men who have retired, women of a certain age (over 50, like me) or millennials who obsess over their brand visibility — we tend to file grievances. When Ralph Ellison’s “Invisible Man” was published in 1952, it was a long overdue cry for recognition — social, judicial, legislative, human — for an entire race. But today, it’s a claim that many more of us seem to think we can file.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">We live in a time and culture that value display and are largely indifferent to the virtues of passing unnoticed. If we don’t get the interest, attention and recognition we think we deserve — whether we are men who have retired, women of a certain age (over 50, like me) or millennials who obsess over their brand visibility — we tend to file grievances. When Ralph Ellison’s “Invisible Man” was published in 1952, it was a long overdue cry for recognition — social, judicial, legislative, human — for an entire race. But today, it’s a claim that many more of us seem to think we can file.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Attention to Detail</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/attention-to-detail/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Attention to Detail" /><published>2022-12-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/attention-to-detail</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/attention-to-detail/">&lt;p&gt;Which makes me wonder if it is time for all of us to reconsider the beauty, elegance and imagination that can come with being unseen. In her 2012 book, “Quiet,” Susan Cain discusses at length how silent attentiveness, rather than active participation, can allow one to absorb “on a deep level the laws of social dynamics” that go on around us. While she makes an eloquent argument for reticence and reserve, the natural world may be even more persuasive.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">Which makes me wonder if it is time for all of us to reconsider the beauty, elegance and imagination that can come with being unseen. In her 2012 book, “Quiet,” Susan Cain discusses at length how silent attentiveness, rather than active participation, can allow one to absorb “on a deep level the laws of social dynamics” that go on around us. While she makes an eloquent argument for reticence and reserve, the natural world may be even more persuasive.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Invisible is not the Equivlaent of Being NonExistent</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/invisible-is-not-the-same-as-not-existing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Invisible is not the Equivlaent of Being NonExistent" /><published>2022-12-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/invisible-is-not-the-same-as-not-existing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/invisible-is-not-the-same-as-not-existing/">&lt;p&gt;They also propose that becoming invisible, whether it is in color or behavior, is not the equivalent of being nonexistent, a lesson the human species seems to resist. It is not about denying creative individualism nor about relinquishing any of the qualities that may make us unique, original, singular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather, it can be a condition of insight and endurance, a position of strength and power, a matter of knowing how and where we can be best accommodated by the exterior world. It can reflect a knowledge that we are of a larger world and that our survival depends on knowing this — not a bad thing to be reminded of when our disruptions of the natural environment result in everything from freakishly warm temperatures to ocean acidification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Invisibility can be about finding a sense of fit with the immediate landscape, be it social, cultural or environmental. It can be about adaptability and the recognition that assertiveness may not always be in our best interest. Most of all, it can reflect a sense of vigilance, a sensitivity to and respect for external conditions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">They also propose that becoming invisible, whether it is in color or behavior, is not the equivalent of being nonexistent, a lesson the human species seems to resist. It is not about denying creative individualism nor about relinquishing any of the qualities that may make us unique, original, singular.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Biological Clock</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/biological-clock/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Biological Clock" /><published>2022-12-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/biological-clock</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/biological-clock/">&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;title: Biological Clock
author: kinlane
categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Biological Clock&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Science&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;light&quot;&gt;Light&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The retina also is home to another type of light-sensitive cell. These melanopsin ganglion (MEH-lah-NOP-sin GANG-lee-un) cells don’t send signals to the occipital cortex. Instead, they report the presence of light to the olivary pretectal nucleus (OH-liv-airy Pree-TEK-tahl NEW-klee-us). This is a tiny spot in the middle of the base of the brain. The signals that melanopsin ganglion cells send here help regulate the body’s master biological clock. They also send signals that control the size of the pupil (which controls how much light gets into the eye in the first place).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Light signals sent to this master body clock tell you when to be sleepy and when to be alert. But not just any light will do. This clock can distinguish between different colors of light. Blue works best to stimulate the body clock. Sunlight is an excellent source of blue light. Although it looks white, sunlight actually is a mix of many colors, including blue. This might explain why stepping outside on a bright sunny day helps clear the fog from your head.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kin Lane</name></author><summary type="html">title: Biological Clock author: kinlane categories: Biological Clock Science Light The retina also is home to another type of light-sensitive cell. These melanopsin ganglion (MEH-lah-NOP-sin GANG-lee-un) cells don’t send signals to the occipital cortex. Instead, they report the presence of light to the olivary pretectal nucleus (OH-liv-airy Pree-TEK-tahl NEW-klee-us). This is a tiny spot in the middle of the base of the brain. The signals that melanopsin ganglion cells send here help regulate the body’s master biological clock. They also send signals that control the size of the pupil (which controls how much light gets into the eye in the first place).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Camouflage and Assumptions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/camouflage-and-assumptions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Camouflage and Assumptions" /><published>2022-12-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/camouflage-and-assumptions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/camouflage-and-assumptions/">&lt;p&gt;Many animals (chameleons, leopards, stick bugs, and arctic hares, to name a few) appear to disappear into their surroundings because of their colour or pattern. Our brains assume that if it looks like the background, it is the background. In every case, our brains make assumptions based on context. Our brains don’t see what our eyes see.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">Many animals (chameleons, leopards, stick bugs, and arctic hares, to name a few) appear to disappear into their surroundings because of their colour or pattern. Our brains assume that if it looks like the background, it is the background. In every case, our brains make assumptions based on context. Our brains don’t see what our eyes see.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Molly Was Keeping the Blinds Closed Now</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/molly-was-keeping-the-blinds-closed-now/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Molly Was Keeping the Blinds Closed Now" /><published>2022-12-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/molly-was-keeping-the-blinds-closed-now</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/molly-was-keeping-the-blinds-closed-now/">&lt;p&gt;Molly couldn’t take it anymore. The neighbor across the way has been standing in his window starting at her for weeks. She had gone to talk to the front desk for their building, but they hadn’t gotten back to her with any response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She began closing all the blinds, except for the one window that overlooked the street and park below. That was the one way she still felt connected to the city, sitting in her chair and watching people throughout the day. They were far enough away that she couldn’t see their faces, but she could still make out their personalities from their clothes and the way they walked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Troy left, this tiny slice of the city was all that she could handle. Her neighbor had just narrowed that slice even further, but she still controlled the street below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">Molly couldn’t take it anymore. The neighbor across the way has been standing in his window starting at her for weeks. She had gone to talk to the front desk for their building, but they hadn’t gotten back to her with any response.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nordstrom Rack and T.J. Max Are Where It is At</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nordstrom-rack-and-tj-max-are-where-it-is-at/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nordstrom Rack and T.J. Max Are Where It is At" /><published>2022-12-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nordstrom-rack-and-tj-max-are-where-it-is-at</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nordstrom-rack-and-tj-max-are-where-it-is-at/">&lt;p&gt;Lauren most enjoyed, and made the most money from lifting things from Nordstrom Rack and T.J. Max. They have some of the best discounted items for brands that sell the best online. And clothes was way more fun to steal, because she had to do more of the “shopping” to look for just the right items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on the layout of the store, “shopping” for just the right items was an art. You don’t want to look suspicious if someone saw you, but you wanted to blend in. Lauren knew what colors the walls of the store were painted, and understand where the cameras and checkout aisles were. She played it all.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">Lauren most enjoyed, and made the most money from lifting things from Nordstrom Rack and T.J. Max. They have some of the best discounted items for brands that sell the best online. And clothes was way more fun to steal, because she had to do more of the “shopping” to look for just the right items.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Perception</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/perception/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Perception" /><published>2022-12-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/perception</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/perception/">&lt;p&gt;Perception is created in part through the simultaneous action of thousands of feature detector neurons — specialized neurons, located in the visual cortex, that respond to the strength, angles, shapes, edges, and movements of a visual stimulus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feature detectors work in parallel, each performing a specialized function. When faced with a red square, for instance, the parallel line feature detectors, the horizontal line feature detectors, and the red colour feature detectors all become activated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This activation is then passed on to other parts of the visual cortex, where other neurons compare the information supplied by the feature detectors with images stored in memory. Suddenly, in a flash of recognition, the many neurons fire together, creating the single image of the red square that we experience.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>kinlane</name></author><summary type="html">Perception is created in part through the simultaneous action of thousands of feature detector neurons — specialized neurons, located in the visual cortex, that respond to the strength, angles, shapes, edges, and movements of a visual stimulus.</summary></entry></feed>